我的天
Oh, my God!
威廉森 快进来
Williamson, get in here!
这里怎么回事
What the hell happened in here?
一点小意外
An accident.
赶紧把他送去医务室 快
Let me get in here.Hold on. Come on
出去
Get out
我以为你只是想和他说些悄悄话
I thought you said you were gonna have a conversation with him
没错
Yeah, I did
事情有点过火而已
Things... escalated.
我们需要帮忙
We need some help here.
带他去3号房
Bring him on into three
凯希 给他十毫升麻醉药
Kathy, I'm gonna need 10ccs of Xylocaine
感谢帮忙 我来处理这事吧
Thanks, guys. I'll take it from here
我说了 谢谢 我会处理的
I said thank you. I'll take it from here
走吧
Let's go
好的
OK
让我看看你的脚
Let's take a look at you
你会没事的
You're OK. You're OK
发生了什么
What happened?
没什么
Nothing
这是没什么吗 迈克尔
This isn't nothing?Michael
我要知道发生了什么
I need you to tell me what happened
不要逼我对你说谎
Don't make me lie to you
拜托
Please
我希望内务部能对这件事进行调查
I think you had better start an investigation
不需要
Oh, there's no need.
我们很清楚发生了什么
We know what happened
那麻烦你告诉我
Perhaps you'd been good enoughto enlighten me
地上有一把除草剪刀
There was a pair of gardening shears
就在他工作的小屋子里
On the floor of the shed
很明显 他踩了上去
He stepped on them
然后刀锋直接穿过了鞋割伤了他的脚
The blade went right through his boot, huh?
是的
Yeah
但是为什么他的脚上没有鞋呢
So why wasn't the boot still on his foot?
我说过了 医生
Like I said, Doctor
我们已经搞定了这件事
We got it taken care of
走吧
Let's go
-我要把那个混蛋杀了  -不行
-I'll kill that scum.  -You won't.
你杀了他就等于扼杀了我们离开的机会
You kill him, you kill our ticket out of here
看他对你做了什么
Look what he did to you
我怕你活不过下一秒钟
You won't last a second here
如果我不做点什么
Unless I do something about it
你听过顶点飞行公司吗
You ever hear of Top Flight Charters?
听过
Yeah
他们运作中西部 一些小型机场的航线
They operate flights from small airfields in the Midwest
那公司离这里不到10英里
Like the one ten miles away.
属于阿布鲁奇名下的空壳公司
They're run by a shell corporation Abruzzi owns
如果我们跟他合作
We get him on board
就可以保证我们能在越狱的当晚
there'll be a flight for us
坐上飞机销声匿迹
The night we get outside these walls.
你愿意把逃亡的成败
You're willing to risk the entire escape
寄托在这个你根本不了解的人身上
On a guy you don't even know?
谋事在人
Preparation can only take you so far
但成事在天
After that, you gotta take a few leaps of faith
我不相信阿布鲁奇是可以信任的
Abruzzi's a huge leap of faith
不仅仅是阿布鲁奇
I'm not talking about Abruzzi
还有一人是关键人物
There's someone else who holds the key to this entire thing
有了他 才决定最后是成功还是失败
It either works or it doesn't
问题是
Problem is
我要进来以后 才能肯定这个人是谁
I couldn't know who that was until he got in here
苏克雷
Sucre?
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious
那是一个贼 你不能相信他
The guy's a thief, Michael. He can't be trusted
必须相信他
Gonna have to trust him
因为他是我的室友
Because he's my cellmate
你对他了解多少
How well do you know him?
认识了不过一周
About as well as a man can in a week.
你告诉他等于告诉所有人
You tell him, he tells everyone
那样我们就完了 你明白吗
We're done.You know that, right?
他不加入的话
If he's not on board
我没法在牢房做任何事
There's no digging in that cell
如果真的是这样
And if there's no digging
逃亡只是做梦
Then there's no escape
你好 请在 嘀 一声后留下口讯
Thank you for calling.Please leave a message after the tone
玛丽克鲁兹
Maricruz
是我 亲爱的 你在吗
It's me, baby. Are you there?
你在的话接电话 我被关禁闭了
Pick up if you're there, Mari.I've been in the SHU
我一直很想你
I've been thinking about you
想你迷人的身体
About your body
我一直在想你的身体
God, I've been thinking about your body
你好
Hello?
德尔加多太太
Mrs Delgado...
你好吗
Hi, how you doing?
我是费尔南多
It's me, Fernando
抱歉打扰你
Sorry to bother you at home
你知道玛丽克鲁兹的手机怎么了吗
Do you know what's up with Maricruz's cellphone?
一直都打不通 都是留言信箱
It just keeps going straight to voice mail
她大概把手机关掉了
Maybe she has it turned off
请问你知道她在哪里吗
Any chance you know where she is?
我当然知道
I know exactly where she is.
她在哪里
And that would be?
-和赫克特在一起   -赫克特
-With Hector.  -Hector?
是的
That's right
他们出去逛街了 我想
They're at the mall, I think
你不想我再见她了
I don't suppose next time you see her
你是不是能让她把手机打开
You could have her turn her phone back on?
德尔加多太太 我知道你不喜欢我
Mrs Delgado, I know you don't like me
但我爱你女儿 她也爱我
But I love your daughter and she loves me
我们快结婚了 你知道吗
We're gonna get married, you know?
如果你是一个明白人 你也真正爱她的话
If you were a decent man,and you really loved her
就不要再缠着她了
You'd let her live her life
这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我会告诉她你打过电话来
I'll tell her you called
我想搞点破坏
I'm looking to do some damage
那你来对地方了
Well, you've come to the right place.
我要慢慢的那种
I want to do it slow.
造成最大痛苦的
Inflict the maximum amount of pain
让人求死不能
So a guy wishes he'd die
你明白的 就是那种快死了
And get it over with,
但又不会去见上帝的那种
But just can't quite get there.
明白
Oh, I got that.
明白了
I got that.
来看看这个吧 老大
Look at this right here, boss.
我宝贝的收割者
I call it the gutter.
从胃那里插进去
You jam it in the stomach.
肠子都给拉出来
These bits hook the intestines.
只要轻轻一拉
You give it a pull back
那个可怜虫的内脏会乱成一团
poor sucker's guts are hanging right out of his stomach
他会像你说的那样
And he'll get a real good look at emcos
求死不能
The wound's not fatal
至少在伤口感染之前不会死
At least not until the infection sets in.
你真是一个变态的家伙 你知道吗
You're one sick puppy,you know that?
谢谢
Thank you.
你怎么了
What happened?
我很好
I'm OK.
他们打你了吗
They've gotten to you, haven't they?
那些囚犯
The other prisoners.
天呢 迈克尔 这地方会让你送命的
My God, Michael, this place is gonna kill you.
你说你跟一个女人有接触
You said you talked to a woman.
-她叫什么  -莱提莎
-What was her name?  -Leticia
-莱提莎・巴里斯  -你怎么知道
-Leticia Barris.  -How'd you know?
一年前 我也在做你现在同样的事情
A year ago I was doing exactly what you're doing
试图找出真相
Trying to find out the truth.
结果什么都没查到 维罗妮卡
It's a bottomless pit, Veronica.
他们都设计好了
They designed it
一旦你穷追不舍
So that when you got to the bottom of it
林肯也会被杀
Lincoln would be dead
你为什么不告诉我你也一直在查这事
Why didn't you tell me you were doing this ?
一旦日子定下来
Once the day was set
最终上诉被驳回
Once that final appeal had been rejected
他只剩下60天的时间
he had 60 days to live
我们不能任由他们摆布
I figured I could play their game
眼睁睁看着他死
and watch him die in the process
我要把事情掌握在自己手里
Or take matters into my own hands.
你不需要这样做
You don't have to do that
莱提莎知道一些东西 我要找出来
Leticia knows something. If I can get it out of her
也许能重开林肯的案子
Maybe we can reopen the case
她说什么了
What'd she tell you ?
她说有人
Somebody else
是这策划谋杀副总统兄弟的幕后黑手
was behind the killing of the vice president's brother.
谁 她走掉了
Who? She took off
在她说出来前就走掉了
Before I got anything out of her.
她是乐土计划的一部分
She's holed up in the Elysian Fields project.
我和她约了今天下午见面
I'll go see her this afternoon.
那地方很危险
That place is dangerous.
找人陪你去
Take someone with you.
谁
Who?
可能你的未婚夫会是一个好人选
Fiance'd be a good place to start.
我想这会是他最不愿意做的一件事
I think that's probably the last thing in the world Sebastian would ever want to do.
见到你真好
It's good to see you.
我也是
Me too.
没有前科 一个好学生
No priors, a good student.
因为贩药被抓住
Then you get yourself arrested for intent to sell.
好日子过腻了
Good life get a little boring?
我一时糊涂
It was stupid
不会再发生这样的事情
It won't happen again
我们就是要确认这一点
Well, we're all here to make sure of that
你来之前我跟你母亲聊过
I took some to speak to your mother before you came in
她告诉我其实
She told me that
你这么做是有原因的
there were some extenuating circumstances...
如果你想说在监狱的那个人
If you mean that guy at Fox River,
他跟这事没有一点关系
He's got nothing to do with this.
他拒绝称呼他为父亲
He refuses to call him his father.
这个世界没有他会更好
The world would be better without him.
LJ
你的火气可不小啊 年轻人
It's clear to me you've got a lot of anger, young man.
这样的情绪会让你做错事
It could land you in the wrong place.
为了避免你再犯错
To make sure that doesn't happen,
每周你要向我报到一次
You'll check in with me once a week.
每周五 一小时
Fridays. One hour.
在学校不能无故缺席 成绩要良好
Your grades need to be pristine
当然
Absolutely.
同时我有一个建议
I will give you an really idea
你必须控制你的情绪 而不是被情绪控制
Where that anger will get you if you don't rein it in,
我会让你参加一个监狱辅导计划
I'll sign you up for the programme at Fox River.
在里面 你会有自己的导师
You'll have a mentor who you'll work with weekly.
每周与你见面并给你相关辅导
Give you some perspective.
导师
A mentor?
你的父亲
Your father.
告诉我这不是我想的那东西
Tell me that isn't what I think it is.
这不是你想的那东西
It isn't what you think it is.
小嫩鸡
Fish
你在这里有手机
A cellphone in here?
这是罪加一等
That's cardinal sin number one.
他们会在你刑期上加判你2年
They can tack two years onto your bid.
如果你被捉到的话
If they catch you.
你知道我会有麻烦
You know what trouble
就因为知道这事
I can get for knowing this?
那是不是我现在需要就可以打电话
Now, that means you can make calls whenever you want, right?
我不喜欢你现在的眼神
I don't like the look in your eye.
里面的东西 你从来没见过
What's in there, you never saw it
明白吗
Got it?
你为何不写下任何一个名字
Why didn't you include any names?
我为什么要让别人看着我死去
Why would I want anyone to watch me die?
我见过很多人
I've seen it happen a number of ways.
有些希望独自离去
Some people want to go it alone
而另一些却在死前还在唠唠叨叨
Others have grandiose statements they want to make
当然大部分人希望家人的陪伴
But most want some member of their family there
在他们离开这个世界的时候
Before they leave this world
我选择独自承受
I'll do it alone.
孩子 我的建议是
Son, in my opinion,
选择孤独离去的人
All inmates who have made that choice
多半在临死前 后悔自己的决定
Have deeply regretted it in their final minutes.
我
I'll...
你留着这份申请表
Leave it blank for now.
你剩下不到4周的时间
You have less than four weeks now.
再仔细考虑一下
You should give it some thought.
我要找 莱提莎・巴里斯
Hi, I'm looking for Leticia Barris.
5号房
Five.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好
Hello?
不要动
Don't you move a muscle.
冷静点 莱提莎
Take it easy, Leticia.
你和他们是一伙的 不是吗?
You're working with them , arn't you ?
别把我当傻瓜
You think I'm stupid, lady?
我知道我电话被监听了
I hear the clicks on my phone,
还有停在对面马路的车
I see the cars on the street.
我知道你很害怕 我也是
I know you're scared. I am too.
请你把枪放下
But, please, put the gun down.
你去哪里
Where you going?
爱尔兰 去哪里有何分别
Ireland. What difference does it make?
有分别
All the difference.
你不曾在法庭作供
Nobody got your testimony.
所以我现在还活着
That's the exact reason I'm still breathing.
我不是你的敌人 你一定要相信我
I'm not with them. You have to believe me.
那你偷偷来找我目的何在
What are you sneaking in here for?
我只是担心他们先来抓你
I thought maybe they'd gotten to you.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你为什么这么关心我的处境
Why do you care about my wellbeing
只是一时兴起
All of a sudden?
不是的
I don't.
这才是句真话
Finally, an honest answer.
也许你可以救林肯
But maybe you can save Lincoln.
还有把杀你男友的人
And maybe you can bring down the guys who killed your boyfriend
绳之于法
In the process.
如果被杀的是你
If someone killed you
你男友也会这样做吧
And Crab could've done something to them
你以为他不会吗
You think he would have?
我没有他那么坚强
I'm not as strong as he was
我不能对付那些人
I can't take those people on.
我来对付那些人
I'll take them on.
你只需要来我办公室
All you have to do is come to my office
告诉我你所知道的
And tell me what you know
我会记录下来
I'll type it up
签署一份宣誓书后你就可以离开
You can sign the affidavit and split.
有需要我甚至可以 亲自送你去机场
I'll take you to the airport myself.
巴利克
Bellick.
怎么了 林肯
Hey, what's up, Lincoln?
下几个星期 我需要多一点外出的时间
I want extra time outside for the next two weeks.
但你一定要刷墙的
Paint fumes in PI must be getting to you.
这里允许带手机吗
Cellphones allowed in here?
谁
Who?
额外的放风时间
Extra time outside
还要一些烟
Couple cigarettes
每周半小时
Half-hour one week
一支烟
One cigarette
知道叫苏克雷的家伙
Know a con named Sucre?
我实在不明白 约翰
This is what I don't understand, John
菲波纳奇 指正你
Otto Fibonacci fingers you
他让你下半辈子蹲在大牢里
He put you in prison for life
你似乎对此漠不关心
Yet you act like you don't even want to find out where he is
这不是真的 菲利
That's not true, Philly.
是不是你觉得自己
Maybe you don't think you
已经一无所有了
Have anything to lose any more
你已经在里面了
You're already locked up.
你是不是
Maybe
喜欢呆在里面
You like it here
我不知道
I don't know.
我只是肯定
But what I do know is that
菲波纳奇 会在下月作证
If Fibonacci testifies next month
我快要成为你的邻居了
You and I are gonna be neighbours.
我不会让这一切发生
And I am not going to let that happen
我想你不会适应里面的环境的 菲利
I don't think you would fit in here, Philly.
名牌衬衣 领带和西装
Fancy suits and ties and shirts.
我想你是对的
I think you're right
我不想跟你废话
So let's cut to the chase.
你对付那小子没有
Did you break this kid?
他有没有告诉你 菲波纳奇 的下落
Did he tell you where Fibonacci is?
-这是什么  -一个小礼物
-What is this?  -It's a little gift from me to you.
-这是他的  -他不肯开口
-Are these his?  -Yeah. He won't crack
我想你要另找方法解决这事情
Well, perhaps you should consider using a different methodology then, John
据我所知
From what I gather
有些东西比肉体伤害更能让人屈服
there are far worse threats in prison other than bodily harm
记得以前你信任我
When you used to trust me, Philly
是因为我总能把事情办好
That I would get things done?
以前我信任你
That was
是因为你确实能把事情做好
When you actually did get things done.
爹地
Daddy!
你听到那消息了吗
Did you hear the news?
什么消息
What... what news?
我们会和 菲利 叔叔
We're going to stay with Uncle Philly
一起到湖边玩几个星期
At the lake for a few weeks
是的 我们会玩得很开心
Yeah, and we're gonna have a good time.
你是对的 约翰
You're right, John
我确实信任你
Maybe you're right.I do trust you.
而你不会让我失望的 对吗
Now, you're gonna take care of that thing, aren't you?
你的家属探访怎么样
How are those bone-yard visits
和你女友的那个
Going with that girlfriend of yours?
我想应该很不错吧
I imagine pretty good, huh?
你知道这是
You know visitation rules stipulate that conjugals
已婚犯人的专利
Are only for married couples.
我们订婚了
We're engaged
而且
Besides
我一向安分守纪
I got that coming to me because I ain't caused no static in this place
请不要剥夺我的权利
Please, don't dead my conjugals.
我不会的
I won't.
谢谢
Thank you.
但作为交换
But in exchange
我要你告诉我那手机的事情
You have to tell me where that cellphone is.
手机
Cellphone?
不要装傻
Don't play stupid with me
这是你保住操女人的权利的唯一机会
I'm giving you a chance to save your precious conjugals
如果你说谎 就什么都没了
You lie to me, they're gone
永远都不会有了
And they're never coming back.
那手机在哪里
Where's that cellphone?
特纳
Turner
你的换岗批准了
Your transfer came in.
上头要你负责管理
They want you in administration.
他没开口
He didn't talk.
作为回报 我只想打打电话
All I got to say is I better get to make all the calls I want.
这有点困难
Gonna be kinda hard.
肥皂
Soap?
我因为一块肥皂失去夫妻权利
I lost my conjugals over soap?
你是失去了一点权利
You may have lost your conjugals
但我会给你更多
But I can do you one better
让你们可以在一起
I can get you to her.
和玛丽克鲁兹
With Maricruz?
你让我们在一起 没错
You can get me to Maricruz?That's right
你要怎么做
How you gonna do that?
我们准备越狱
We're breaking out of here.
怎么做
How?
从我们的牢房开始
Starts in our cell
我们的牢房
In our cell?
告诉你
To tell you the truth
已经开始了
It's already started
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你以为我想越狱
You think I want to break out of here?
再过16个月我就出去了
6 months from now I'm at the gate.
我要结婚了
I'm getting married,
我可不想在婚礼时被警察捉回去
And not with no posse on my ass.
伙计 我真想揍你
I oughta beat you six ways till Sunday.
我失去了我的权利
I lost my conjugals
就因为你的肥皂
Because of your little bar of soap.
我必须先测试一下你会不会泄密
I had to see if you could keep a secret.
你要秘密
You want a secret?
我告诉你个秘密
I got a secret for you, fish
你在我的牢房乱搞
You dig in my cell when I'm there
我鸡巴都给你割了
I'm gonna split your wig.
(西班牙语: 你的明白?)
现在安逸了
That went well
我们就从林肯和你男友的关系开始
Let's start with Lincoln's relationship with your boyfriend
很简单
Well,simple.
他欠我男友9万块钱 一直没法还清
He owed my man 90,000.He wasn't getting it done
突然间他有钱了
All of a sudden, it gets done
克拉勃 很高兴地拿着钱回来
Crab walks up with 90k and a big-ass smile
谁给他的钱
Who paid him?
不是林肯 有人帮他付的
Not Lincoln. They paid his marker.
那些人是谁
Who's they?
没事的 你现在很安全
It's all right, Leticia.I told you, you're safe here
我在家里见过他一次 就一次
Crab brought this guy home.Never seen him before
克拉勃 在做大生意的时候
Crab did what he always did
总是叫我出去
He told me to take a walk,so that's exactly what I did
关于那个男人
There was something about this guy
不像是克拉勃经常来往的那种人
He wasn't the kind he usually dealt with.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他们似乎不可冒犯
Couldn't put my finger on it till he went outside
我就知道
Then I knew
有那种感觉
He had that look
-怎样的感觉  -你知道
-What look?  -You know.
就像他们是掌权的人
Like they own the place
有一种权威的感觉
Like they're untouchable
就像是政府的人
Like they're government.
你说政府偿还了林肯的债务
So the government paid Lincoln's debt?
克拉勃有没有说他们想交换什么
Did Crab say what they wanted in return?
没
Uh-uh
好吧
All right
你等我一会把这些东西打好
Just give me a moment to type this up.
-你去哪里  -抽根烟
-Where are you going?  -I'll have a smoke
一分钟就好
This is only gonna take me a minute
我也是
So will the smoke
没有红肿说明没有发炎
No swelling, so there's no sign of infection
再打十天抗生素
I'll keep you on antibiotics for ten days.
你就会没事了
You should be good.
迈克尔 你要明白
Michael .You will understand
按照规矩 我要向上面报告
By law I must file a report
如果我知道囚犯之间有些什么
If I feel there has been prisoner misconduct?
这伤绝不可能是
There's no way this injury happened
意外踏上一把除草剪刀造成的
By stepping on a blade in a garden shed.
你报告上去 事情对我而言会变得更糟
If you file the report,things could get a lot worse.
现在还不够糟
They're not already?
比起他们能做的 这已经算好的了
Not compared to what they could be
我有不少敌人
I've made some enemies
嗯
Yeah
害怕吗
You scared?
好吧
Men. OK
我想你肯定会害怕
Here's what I think. I think you are scared.
如果不害怕那不正常
And you wouldn't be human
在这样的地方
If you weren't scared in a place like this.
我小的时候 晚上总是睡不着
When I was young, I couldn't sleep at night
总觉得衣橱里有怪物在窥视我
Because I thought there was a monster in the closet
我哥哥对我说
But my brother told me
门后面什么也没有 只有你的恐惧
There wasn't anything in the closet but fear,
那不是真实的
And fear wasn't real.
恐惧没有形态
He said it wasn't made of anything.
只是空气
It was just... air.
他还说
Not even that
你必须要面对它
He said you just have to face it
打开那扇门 怪物就会消失不见
You just have to open that door,and the monster would disappear.
你哥哥是一个聪明人
Your brother sounds like a smart man
是的
He is.
虽然在这里
In here, though
你勇敢的打开了门
You face your fear, you open that door,
但你发现后面还有一百扇门你要打开
And there's a hundred more doors behind it
而且门后的怪物
And the monsters that are hiding behind them
全部都是真实的
Are all real
如果你愿意 我可以申请把你送去文书区
If you want,I could recommend you be sent to ad seg
和一群强奸犯和小偷在一起
With the rape victims and the snitches.
这样可以保证你的安全
It would keep you safe.
谢谢
Thanks
我宁愿自己面对那群怪物
but I think I'd like to face the monsters on my own
抽完烟了
Have a good smoke?
我不抽烟
I don't smoke
希望没有吓到你
Didn't mean to startle you.
我是 凯勒曼 探员 特情局的
Special Agent Kellerman, Secret Service.
我们被告知
We've been informed that
你得到了一份保安录像的复本
you obtained a copy of the surveillance tape
是林肯布罗斯一案的重要证据
Entered as evidence in the Burrows trial.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem with that?
我们只是来了解一下
We're just following up
是不是公共资料法有什么更改
Has there been an amendment to the Freedom of Information Act that
我还不知道
I'm not aware of?
你知道当一个死囚
When a prisoner gets
即将行刑之前
close to the end of his time on death row
总是有很多无谓的努力
There's a lot of last-minute...
抱歉 我不明白
I'm sorry.I don't understand
是什么引起特情局的关注
Why this would be a problem for the Secret Service
没有
It's not
只是这案子的判决绝对勿庸置疑
The prosecution made its case far beyond any reasonable doubt
而我们清楚我们抓对了人
and we know that we have the right man
不过 万一你有可能找到
That being said, if you come across anything
证明犯人无罪的证据
That could shed some light on his innocence,
-我们会全力提供协助  -听起来不错
-I'm offering my help.  -Sounds great
感谢你特意告诉我这些
I really appreciate you coming by
你有名片吗 凯勒曼 探员
Do you have a card, Agent Kellerman?
当然
Of course.
随时给我电话
Don't hesitate to call.
当然
Thanks
莱提莎
Leticia
-塞巴斯蒂安 很抱歉  -你在哪里
-Sebastian, I'm so sorry.  -Where are you?
对不起 现在不是时候
This isn't the time. I'm sorry
已经是约定时间 我现在接待室
This is the time. I'm at the reception hall.
中介来了
The coordinator is here
卖家也到了
the vendors is too
听着 我非常抱歉
Look, I-I'm just...I'm sorry
现在不方便说话
I-I can't talk right now
我们把他整条腿卸掉好了
I say we take his whole foot.
我们可以把他的四肢都砍掉
We could cut off all his limbs
但他还是不会说一个字
He still wouldn't talk
痛苦有时不能解决问题
Pain is not the answer here.
或者只有披头士乐队是对的
Maybe the Beatles were right after all
我们需要的只是爱
Maybe all you need is love
你在做什么
What are you doing?
你觉得我在做什么 在收拾东西
What does it look like? I'm rolling it up
你不能这样做
You can't do this
我不会参与你的疯狂计划
I'm done with your reindeer games
我要去一个普通的 正常的牢房
I'm gonna transfer to a nice,quiet cell with a normal cellie
去一个不会把我毁掉的地方
One that doesn't screw my entire life up
听着
Look
对你失去权利我很抱歉
I'm sorry about your conjugals
如果你现在离开
But if you go now...
不要这样 拜托
Don't do this. Please
听我说
Listen to me, fish.
我只有16个月
I got 16 months
我还有未婚妻在外面
I got a fiance to think about
如果我做这样的事
I get caught with a hole in my wall
我要再过五年才能看见外面的世界
I don't get to see the real world for another five years
走吧 苏克雷
Let's go, Sucre
我不会这样做
I can't do that
凡事总有解决的办法 我们可以商量
There is a solution. We can work it out.
对不起 小嫩鸡
Sorry, fish
可以问个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
你为何不愿意
Why have you denied
让家人和至爱陪你走最后一程
any family or loved ones to be there for you in the end?
为何要让他们看着我死去
Why would I let them watch me die?
我已经带来很多痛苦
I've caused them enough pain.
也许并不是他们看着你死去
Maybe it's not about them watching you die.
你意思是我看着他们好好活着
Maybe it's about me watching them live.
-让我因此内心煎熬  -不是的
-That the final torture?  -No
在你离开这个世界的时候
It's about how you want to leave this world.
你希望最后带走怎样的影像
What's the last image you want to take with you?
一个陌生人
A stranger?
想对那边的小朋友做什么
Got an issue with our little friend over there?
不需要你同意
You don't need consent
这跟你没什么关系
You don't give the green light.
这里的所有事情都需要我的同意
Everything in here runs through me.
你知道的
You know that.
梅・塔格 就是因为他才死了
May Tag's in the ground because of that piece of detritus
所以你要他偿还
So now you want him
用他剩下的每一天
Every day for the rest of his bid.
似乎英雄所见略同
Seems you and I have something in common
进去
Get in!
放松点 小嫩鸡
Easy, now, fish
不要让大家都不好过
Don't make this any harder than it needs to be
下面我们将会有些安排
It's time we came to an arrangement
你不反对吧
Don't you think?
我在想怎样把你的内脏狠狠地取出
You know, I was thinking I was gonna gut you bow to stern
就在我们眼神接触的瞬间
As soon as I laid eyes on you
我想你痛苦的样子一定很漂亮 不是吗
But, alackaday, you look so pretty when you're scared, don't you?
也是我爱的表达方式
I'll get the love out of the way
爱到极点就是恨
Before the hate
你觉得呢 帅哥
What do you say, pretty?
也许是时候我们好好了解一下对方
Maybe it's time I lit up that leather once and for all, huh?
鸟人废话是多
God, he talks too much.
我们需要好好聊聊
You and I need to have a conversation.
里面发生的事表明了我的态度
What happened in there was my way of saying
之前我们有点小误会
I know I've been going about this whole thing the wrong way.
我想表示一点歉意
I'm trying to make amends here
过去的就过去了
Bygones be bygones
你真善变啊 约翰
You're a mercurial man, John
我更认为是有胆识
I prefer bold.
说你想从我这里得到什么
Tell me what you need from me
交易
A trade
你给我飞机
You get me a plane
我给你 菲波纳奇
And I'll get you Fibonacci
你要飞机做什么
What do you need a plane for?
我想你知道的
I think you know
我帮你的话 我也搅进去了
I help you, I'm in
你知道的 对吧
You know that, don't you?
当然
I do
我要知道准确的日期和时间
Just gotta know the exact date and time
很快我会告诉你
I'll tell you soon enough
迟则作废
Soon enough won't cut it
在 菲波纳奇 作证之前
I need to be outside before Fibonacci testifies
没问题
You will be
只有不到一个月了
He testifies in one month
还有很多时间
Then you'll be out in plenty of time
如果做不到 你死定了
If not, you're a corpse
长话短说
So cut the crap
我要知道日期和时间
Tell me the exact date and time
我才能安排
So I can start making the arrangements
我还不确定是否应该相信你
I don't know if I can trust you yet
为什么
Why not?
我说过了 因为你很善变
Like I said, John, you're a mercurial man
路易斯 把这些解开
Lewis, take these off
我不能这样做
Sink, I can't do that
伙计 我在牢里
Come on, man. I'm in a cage
十分钟
Ten minutes
求你
Please
是我儿子
It's my kid
我们又见面了
So, here we are
是的
Yeah
你怎么样阿
How you been?
你知道的 有点麻烦
You know, in trouble.
你妈妈呢
How's your mom?
很好
She's good
我跟牧师聊天
I've been talking to the chaplain
他们要我决定谁 呃
They'd like me to decide on who I should have at the...
我想说的是
I guess what I'm trying to say is...
直到最后一刻 你才会意识到
When you get to the end,you start to realise
什么是最重要的
What's important to you
谁是无法取代的人
You know, who really matters to you.
然后 你知道
And, you know
我说的是你和迈克尔
That leaves you and Mike
唯一与我有血缘关系的亲人
The only blood I got left in this...
在这个世界上
this world
我想说
Yeah, I gotta say
我不是很懂你在说什么
I'm not really following what you're saying
只是
Well, uh...
到了最后
In the end
我的心里只剩下爱
The only thing that matters is love
血缘 家人 还有 你
Blood, family, you
给我你的手
Um...Give me your hand
你在做什么
What are you doing?
给我你的手
Give me your hand
你的手
我想你能来
I want you to be there when...
在我行刑的那天
I want you to be there the day before I die.
让我看见你
So I can see you.
我可以抱抱你
So I can hold you.
我
I...
我爱你
I love you
我一直都爱你
I've always loved you
这一切
This whole thing...
我不知能否能够承受
I don't know if I can take it
我也是
Me either
但我别无选择
I don't have a choice
但你有
You do
我很抱歉
I am so sorry
今早我和一位女士会面
I met with this woman today
她知道林肯案子的一些内情
And she knew things about Lincoln's case
然后她就消失了
Then she just disappeared
我想她出事了
I think something happened to her
听着
Look.
我尽量把话说得简单点
I'm gonna make this real easy for you
你还想跟我结婚吗
Do you want to get married
还是不想
Or not?
我不知道
I don't know
很好
Wonderful
或许我们可以延期
Maybe we could postpone it
现在我不能
I can't do this right now
我没心思在这上面
I had thoughts in it
这应该是一件值得高兴的事
It's supposed to be a celebration...
如果你这样说
If you're really telling me
你希望延期婚礼
You want to postpone this thing
那么我想还是算了吧
then I want to cancel it.
塞巴斯蒂安
Sebastian
很抱歉
I'm sorry
明天我来收拾自己的东西
I'll come and get my stuff tomorrow
打开40号
Open on 40
斯科菲尔德
Scofield
你有新狱友了
Found you a new cellie
你运气不错在精神病区转送过来一个人
I found him in psych ward
因为只有你这里还有空位
You were the only guy with an empty tray
精神病区
Psych ward?
你有意见吗
You got a problem with that?
有的话
Cos if you do
你可以把意见放进我的建议箱
Please feel free to drop it into my suggestion box here
海威尔 进来
Haywire, get in here
40号 关门
Close it up on 40
斯科菲尔德
Scofield
提醒你
Just a heads-up
不要跟他有眼神接触
Don't make eye contact with him.
林肯 我们有麻烦了
Lincoln, we have a problem
-我有一个新的室友  -谁
-I got a new cellmate.  -Who?
这真是一个麻烦
That's a problem
只好把他拉进来
We'll just have to bring him on board.
这样的人可帮不上忙
You don't bring a guy like that on board
那只有等他睡觉以后才能干活
I'll work when he's sleeping
离开十步 斯科菲尔德
Ten feet, Scofield
-我们进度滞后几天  -3天
-How far behind are we?   -Three days
你说过我们没有时间可以浪费
I thought you said the margin for error was zero days
是的
I did
这地方真不错
Nice out here.
我有一个朋友
I've got a buddy.
在这附近的森林有栋房子
He's got a place way back up in these woods.
每年这个时候就来这里打猎
Come up here hunting around this time of year.
把她弄出去
Get her back in. Back in.
来
Come on.
过来
Over here. Come here.
带她去那边
Take her out there.
她无关紧要
She's nothing.
即使她说了什么也没人相信
Nobody would believe her if she talked, anyway.
找个一百码的地方搞定她
Hundred yards or so should do it.
快去
Do it.
去
Go.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你要相信我
You got to believe that.
糟糕
Damn it.
求求你
Please!
处理一下
Pick up the casings.
怎么了阿
What's your problem?
我有神经损伤
I got a neuroanatomic lesion
影响到我脑袋的网状活化系统
affecting my reticular activating system.
是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是我不用睡觉
It means I don't sleep.
完全不用
At all.